<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nokia | this has yet to be defined]]></title>
  <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/blog/categories/nokia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-15T14:27:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://y2bd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[y2bd]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rendering BitmapImages with the Nokia Imaging SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/rendering-bitmapimages-with-the-nokia-imaging-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T14:04:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/rendering-bitmapimages-with-the-nokia-imaging-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I was working on integrating the Nokia Imaging SDK for my journal app, <a href="http://blog.y2bd.me/sofa/">Sofa</a>, for the <a href="http://developer.nokia.com/create/">Nokia Create contest</a>, essentially letting the user crop and enhance their photos before attaching them to an entry.</p>

<p>I found myself using the SDK in my ViewModel and wondering how I was supposed to get the rendered image into my View. The SDK itself provides methods for rendering to JPEG, raw Bitmaps, WriteableBitmaps, and even Image controls. The Image controls option (<code>renderToImageAsync()</code>) sounded like the way to go, but I realized that in the VM I don&rsquo;t have access to the Image control in my view. Instead, I have access to a BitmapImage that binds to the Source property of the Image control. So how do you get a BitmapImage out of the editing session?</p>

<p>Well after some searching I found that you can coax a BitmapImage out of a WriteableBitmap. Here&rsquo;s an extension method that lets you do exactly that:</p>

<p>``` csharp
public static async Task<BitmapImage> RenderToBitmapImageAsync(this IEditingSession session, int width, int height, OutputOption outputOption = OutputOption.PreserveAspectRatio)
{
  var bi = new BitmapImage();</p>

<p>  var wbp = new WriteableBitmap(width, height);
  await session.RenderToWriteableBitmapAsync(wbp, outputOption);</p>

<p>  using (var ms = new MemoryStream())
  {</p>

<pre><code>wbp.SaveJpeg(ms, width, height, 0, 100);
bi.SetSource(ms);
</code></pre>

<p>  }</p>

<p>  // not super necessary
  wbp = null;</p>

<p>  return bi;
}
```</p>

<p>Just put this into a static class (perhaps an Extensions.cs?) and then call</p>

<p><code>csharp
myBindedImage = await _myEditSession.RenderToBitmapImageAsync(someWidth, someHeight, outputOptionIfYouWant);
</code></p>

<p>Note that <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=writeablebitmap+memory+leak">there may be memory issues with WriteableBitmaps</a>, so be wary of calling this often, especially with high widths and heights. You may need to force garbage collection after a few calls.</p>

<p>Because of that, I&rsquo;m definitely not 100% keen on this method. It definitely works (wait for Sofa v1.1 to prove that) but I&rsquo;ll be on the lookout for less memory-intensive options.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
