<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sofa | this has yet to be defined]]></title>
  <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/blog/categories/sofa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-18T17:45:42-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://y2bd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[y2bd]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rendering Image Sources with the Nokia Imaging SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/rendering-bitmapimages-with-the-nokia-imaging-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T14:04:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/rendering-bitmapimages-with-the-nokia-imaging-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Edit</strong>: After some searching, I&rsquo;ve found the Nokia-Certified&trade; method of rendering to a BitmapImage/ImageSource.</p>

<p>First of all, Image controls can surprisingly take a WriteableBitmap as their source. You can do this:</p>

<p>``` csharp</p>

<p>BindedImageSource = new WriteableBitmap(1024,768);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>and everything will be fine.</p>

<p>Second, remember how <code>IEditingSession</code> has a <code>RenderToWriteableBitmap()</code> method?</p>

<p>``` csharp</p>

<p>var myWBP = new WriteableBitmap(1024, 768);</p>

<p>await _session.RenderToWriteableBitmapAsync(myWBP);</p>

<p>myWBP.Invalidate(); // forces a redraw</p>

<p>BindedImageSource = myWBP;</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>An interesting side-note is that RenderToWriteableBitmap appears to be shorthand for</p>

<p>``` csharp</p>

<p>var bitmap = myWBP.AsBitmap();
await _session.RenderToBitmapAsync(bitmap);</p>

<p>```</p>

<p><code>bitmap</code> in this example is not a typical Bitmap, but a <a href="http://developer.nokia.com/Resources/Library/Imaging_API_Ref/#!nokiainteropserviceswindowsruntime-namespace/writeablebitmapextensions-class/writeablebitmapextensions-methods/asbitmap-method.html">mysterious object that wraps a WriteableBitmap&rsquo;s pixel data</a>. That means that changes to this bitmap <strong>affect the original WriteableBitmap</strong>. Now extracting it isn&rsquo;t very helpful in this small example, but if you check out the code for <a href="http://developer.nokia.com/Resources/Library/Lumia/#!nokia-imaging-sdk/sample-projects/filter-effects.html">Nokia&rsquo;s Filter Effects sample</a> (spefically checkout the <code>AbstractFilter</code> class) you can do some pretty neat things without having to create a new WriteableBitmap each time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll keep the original post below for context.</p>

<hr />

<p>So I was working on integrating the Nokia Imaging SDK for my journal app, <a href="http://blog.y2bd.me/sofa/">Sofa</a>, for the <a href="http://developer.nokia.com/create/">Nokia Create contest</a>, essentially letting the user crop and enhance their photos before attaching them to an entry.</p>

<p>I found myself using the SDK in my ViewModel and wondering how I was supposed to get the rendered image into my View. The SDK itself provides methods for rendering to JPEG, raw Bitmaps, WriteableBitmaps, and even Image controls. The Image controls option (<code>renderToImageAsync()</code>) sounded like the way to go, but I realized that in the VM I don&rsquo;t have access to the Image control in my view. Instead, I have access to a BitmapImage that binds to the Source property of the Image control. So how do you get a BitmapImage out of the editing session?</p>

<p>Well after some searching I found that you can coax a BitmapImage out of a WriteableBitmap. Here&rsquo;s an extension method that lets you do exactly that:</p>

<p>``` csharp
public static async Task<BitmapImage> RenderToBitmapImageAsync(this IEditingSession session, int width, int height, OutputOption outputOption = OutputOption.PreserveAspectRatio)
{
  var bi = new BitmapImage();</p>

<p>  var wbp = new WriteableBitmap(width, height);
  await session.RenderToWriteableBitmapAsync(wbp, outputOption);</p>

<p>  using (var ms = new MemoryStream())
  {</p>

<pre><code>wbp.SaveJpeg(ms, width, height, 0, 100);
bi.SetSource(ms);
</code></pre>

<p>  }</p>

<p>  // not super necessary
  wbp = null;</p>

<p>  return bi;
}
```</p>

<p>Just put this into a static class (perhaps an Extensions.cs?) and then call</p>

<p><code>csharp
myBindedImage = await _myEditSession.RenderToBitmapImageAsync(someWidth, someHeight, outputOptionIfYouWant);
</code></p>

<p>Note that <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=writeablebitmap+memory+leak">there may be memory issues with WriteableBitmaps</a>, so be wary of calling this often, especially with high widths and heights. You may need to force garbage collection after a few calls.</p>

<p>Because of that, I&rsquo;m definitely not 100% keen on this method. It definitely works (wait for Sofa v1.1 to prove that) but I&rsquo;ll be on the lookout for less memory-intensive options.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sofa is done!]]></title>
    <link href="http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/sofa-is-done/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-09T21:26:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://y2bd.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/sofa-is-done</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/posts/sofa.png" title="&lsquo;The read, new, and photos views.&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been almost two months now, but Sofa, my journal application for Windows Phone 8, is finally done!</p>

<p>First of all, the last time I referred to Sofa I called it &lsquo;Quill&rsquo;. That was its work-in-progress name, but I had to change it because I couldn&rsquo;t find a nice quill vector to use as the main logo. No problem, Sofa was actually how I referred to the app within the code anyway, and it&rsquo;s still a nice title. Maybe I&rsquo;ll use Quill for something else&hellip;</p>

<p>This is easily the biggest programming project (hell, maybe even general project) that I&rsquo;ve worked on, and I&rsquo;ve learned a <em>ton</em> since I started. I now have a much better grip on Git, and by that I mean I know more than <code>git commit -am "Did stuff"</code> and <code>git push origin master</code>. I learned more about branching, merging, stashing (ran into a nasty problem with that), and am currently learning about rebasing because I have way too many one-line-changed commits.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also learned a lot more about the tools and libraries I&rsquo;ve been using in my small WP dev &lsquo;career&rsquo;. From the Windows Phone Toolkit (which I ended up having to fork to fix a bug), to MVVMLight (minimal code-behind, I promise!), to new tools like SQLite and Microsoft&rsquo;s LiveSDK (for SkyDrive integration, need those bullet-point features).</p>

<p>I <em>think</em> I&rsquo;ve also learned to finally accept a v1 product&mdash;there are tons of features that I want for Sofa, but I needed to realize that if I spend way too much time trying to perfect it, I&rsquo;ll fall into my trap of getting frustrated, getting bored, and then giving up on it altogether (I have enough half-finished VS solutions to show the effects of this).</p>

<p>The last week and a half have been spent with some <em>awesome</em> beta testers who have been extremely helpful in finding bugs, little quirks, and feature suggestions. I am definitely having beta periods for all of my serious apps from now on.</p>

<p>Sofa has been in the approval process for the last two days and you wouldn&rsquo;t believe how nervous I am. Every morning I wake up, scramble to my phone, and falter, looking at that mail icon with a number next to it. I&rsquo;ve gotten &ldquo;Certification Failed&rdquo; for my other apps before (Dammit Pinned, get along with the budget phones!), and I really don&rsquo;t want that to happen now. There&rsquo;s two weeks until I have to move back to Southern California for college, and I have no idea what kind of free time I&rsquo;ll have once that happens.</p>

<p>Wish me luck!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
